Guide to the Harry Gamboa Jr. Papers, 1968-1995
Department of Special Collections
- Series VI: Oversized Publications, Newspapers.
  - Alt: Cal Arts Newlsetter 2/90 (Box 10)
  - Argonaut 4/19/88 (Box 10)
  - Artweek 7/29/78; 9/29/79; 6/5/82; 10/20/84; 11/4/89; 4/95 (Box 10)
  - Bulletin/Calendar: Washington State University 4/15.86 (Box 10)
  - Cal Arts Current 11-12/90 (Box 10)
  - Catolicos Para la Raza 8/70 (Box 10)
  - Civic Center News 1/13/81 (Box 10)
  - Collegian 5/13/92 (Box 10)
  - Communicator 4/22/88 (Box 10)
  - La Communidad 2/8/81; 4/26/81; 1/23/83; 2/6/83; 8/7/83; 4/8/84; 7/5/84; 8/5/84; 9/1/85; 9/22/85; 4/12/87 (Box 10)
  - El Día 6/78 (Box 10)
  - Festival 90 8/26/90 (Box 10)
  - Foco 10/12/76 (Box 10)
  - Forty-Niner 2/22/73 (Box 10)
  - Forum 11/78 (Box 10)
  - Home 6/2/74 (Box 10)
  - L.A. Style 2/87 (Box 10)
  - L.A. Times 8/7/83; 10/5/85; 3/7/88; 4/18/89; 1/8/95 (Box 10)
  - L.A. Weekly 5/86; 2/87; 6/88; 12/94 (Box 11)
  - MALDEF 1978 (Box 11)
  - Mecha Cal State University Los Angeles newspaper 1973 (Box 11)
  - New University 10/9/89 (Box 11)
  - Notes from the Chair Fall 1992 (Box 11)
  - La Opinion 7/13/80; 11/16/80; 5/20/82 (Box 11)
  - Oversight 1990 (Box 11)
  - La Raza c. 1970 (Box 11)
  - Revista Literaria de El Tocolote 1983 (Box 11)
  - La Semana de las Bellas Artes 9/20/78; 9/27/78 (Box 11)
  - El Semanario L.A. 5/5/78 (Box 11)
  - Tin Tan Fall 1987 (Box 11)
  - University Times 11/19/94 (Box 11)
  - URB 2/94 (Box 11)
  - Women's Accomplishments 6/2/82 (Box 11)
  - Xhismearte c. 1981 (Box 11)
  - Miscellaneous clippings re: Chicano Civil Rights Movement c. 1968-1971 (Box 11)
  - Miscellaneous envelopes from correspondence. (Box 11)
- Series VII: Original artwork and miscellaneous
  - Garfield High School Yearbook 1969 (Box 12)
  - Original layouts for "Ahora lo Veras" 1972"Autologue" 1976and "Genocide Patrol" 1971 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Original artwork: "Mi Culpa, Tu Culpa" 1978left and right exhibition boards used in "Ancient Roots/New Visions" exhibit; original layout for "No Slapstick" mail art. (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Untitled drawing on postboard 1973Polaroid photographs from "Echoes in the Impasse" 1971photo: "Belted Consent" from "The Visual Statement" exhibit 1991 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Exchibition poster: ASCO 1981at Cal State San Bernadino; computer printout of Diego Gamboa c. 1985 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Micro film box.9mm shell casing from gun fired in videotaping of "L.A. Familia" 1993Chicano Power buttons 1970, 1972and ASCO/no movie button 1982designed by Gamboa. (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Harry Gamboa Jr. slidebook large black binderSee full slide listing at end of guide. (Box 13)
  - Gamboa audio recordings: 9 audio cassettes. See audio tape listing at end of guide. (Box 14)
  - Gamboa video recordings: 13 video cassettes. See video tape listing at end of guide. (Box 15)
  - Drawing, pen and ink, "Gronk and Herrón" by Gamboa 1972 (Box 16 (oversized))
  - Exhibition posters: "ASCO 83" 1983"Dia de los Muertos/Day of the Dead" 1989"Gamboa 84" 1984"Jetter's Jinx" 1986"The Visual Statement" 1991 (Box 16 (oversized))
  - "Mi Culpa, Tu Culpa" 1978mixed media, center exhibition board: original artwork by Gamboa used in "Ancient Roots/New Visions" exhibit. (Box 16 (oversized))
- Series VIII: Addendum
  Accession 96-143 August 1996
  - Exhibition materials and miscellaneous
    - Harry Gamboa, Jr. selected biography. (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - The John D. and Catherine T. MacArthur Foundation 1994 Summer Graduate Internship. (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Ignore the Dents. (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous exhibition brochures. (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Publications
    - LA. Times Magazine Mar. 27, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - High Performance Fall 1989 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - MALDEF.- Looking to the 1980'slLa Pr6xima Dicada 1979 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Newspapers (no folders) by date. (Box 17)
    - La Opinion July 13, 1980
    - USA Today May 17,1983
    - Los Angeles Times Calendar Aug. 7, 1983
    - I-A Weekly May 16-22,1986
    - LA Extra May 16-22, 1986
    - Albuquerque Journal: The Arts Feb 28, 1992
    - The MOCA Contemporary Feb/Mar 1992
    - Daily News: I-A Life Oct. 21, 1992
- Series IX: Photographs Interfiled with Papers
  - Polaroid: Diego Gamboa and George Silk in "Antizona" 1987 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - From "Connections 2" fliers: Polaroids, Harry T. Gamboa, Diego Gamboa 1994; BW photo, Diego Gamboa. c. 1985 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - CARA/ASCO photographs: Gamboa and others in "Dia de los Muertos", taken by Diane Gamboa 1974; Gronk and Humberto Sandoval in "Jetter's Jinx", taken by Harry Gamboa Jr. c. 1985; Gamboa and others in "First Supper [After a Major Riot]", taken by Harry Gamboa Jr. 1974 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Gamboa photographing a woman with a shopping cart. BW photo by Frank Odel 1989 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - BW photos by Dirk Westphal sent as postcards to Gamboa c. 1989-1991; BW photo by Dirk Westphal c.1989 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - 18 Polaroids portraits incl. Harry Gamboa Jr.from Gamboa seminar at Cal Arts c. 1989; 8 BW photographs of Cal Arts seminar, student presentations c. 1989 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Gamboa, Max Benavídez and Humberto Sandoval. Photo by Diane Gamboa 1984 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Photo postcard by Robert Buitrón; 4 photos of Gamboa by Buitrón, included in correspondence 1983 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - 3 BW photos: Barbara Carrasco and Harry Gamboa Jr. 1982; Carrasco, taken by Gamboa 1987; Carrasco, Diego Gamboa and Martin Sheen, taken by Gamboa 1988. Color photo: Gamboa, Diego Gamboa, and Barbara Gamboa, taken by Carrasco 1984 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Polaroid of Sean Carillo and Gronk in art exhibit, taken by Gamboa 1980; color photo of Gamboa by Carillo 1981; BW art photo with poem by Carillo 1981 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Harry Gamboa Jr. in "Philliphe", color photo by Armando Cristeto 1991. Cyclona, color photo by A. Friedkin. RESTRICTION: Do not reproduce photo of CYCLONA 1994 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Photographs by Diane Gamboa: "Back Stabbing Party" performance during the reception of "The Urban Dessert" exhibition c. 1994; photo of Diego and Harry Gamboa by Diane Gamboa 1983 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Diego and Harry Gamboa 1985; Harry Gamboa Jr. and Barbara Carrasco, photo by Diego Gamboa 1992 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Polaroid of Arthur Marchand 1980 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Postcard from Richard Montoya including 2 color pictures of Gamboa photographic exhibit at Luna's Cafe 1985; color photo-postcard from Montoya of performance 1989 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - ASCO members n.d.; Gamboa filming "Imperfecto" 1982; Gamboa and Carrasco inside card from Sandra Sandoval c.1993 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Gronk, Patssi Valdez and Gamboa 1978 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Gamboa, photo by Ricardo Valverde 1981; Gamboa, photo by Rick Corrales 1983 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Gamboa and Willie Varela 1992 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Color photo card: Apolina, Zaneta and Zaragosa Vargas n.d.; Polaroids: Zaneta Vargas, Zaragosa Vargas n.d.; BW photo: Zaragosa Vargas from "Chicano Male Unbonded" series by Harry Gamboa Jr. (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - 4 Polaroids: Gronk, Humberto Sandoval, Willie Herrón, Diego and Harry Gamboa 1980; Henry Guttierrez at the "Illegal Landscape" reception 1980; Gamboa and others 1981; "Dreva" [?] 1983 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - ASCO members (photograph) 19741975 (Box 12, Folder loose)
- Series X: Photocopies of Photographs Interfiled with Papers
  - Photographs by Gamboa in "Past Imperfrecto" manuscript: Harry Gamboa Jr., Diego Gamboa and Barbara Carrasco in "No Supper" 1987; Gerardo Velazquez from "Chicano Male Unbonded" series by Gamboa 1991 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - From "Refractions of Home" by Gamboa: Humberto Sandoval [?] 1994; Diego Gamboa and Barbara Carrasco. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - From "Where They Found Javier" by Gamboa: "Urban Mummy in Varrio Loco Sweatshirt" 1992; "Assaulted, Arrested, No Contest"; "Javier and the Other Monoliths" [model: Max Benavidez]. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - From "Focus on the Invisible: The Urban Realism of John Valadez" by Gamboa: John Valadez n.d.; painting by Valadez n.d. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - From "Lorena's Lament" by Gamboa: Diego and Harry Gamboa c.1987 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - From "Connections 2" fliers: Harry T. Gamboa and Diego Gamboa 1994; Diego Gamboa c.1985 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - From: The Urban Myths of Almarez" by Gamboa: Carlos Almarez, 2 photos of Almarez paintings; 2 postcards of Max Benavidez n.d. (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - From "The Missing Mural of Aztlan" by Gamboa: Barbara Carrasco; youth workers; Carrasco murals n.d. (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Color Xerox photo notebook By Sean Carillo of Gamboa exhibit "Brown in Black and White" 1982 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Color photocopy: Harry T. Gamboa and Carmen Gamboa [?] with "Colonial Failure Kit" art installation by Gamboa. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - "Half Life Mask" series of manipulated photos of Gamboa by Gerardo Velazquez 1989 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Computer printout of Diego Gamboa n.d. (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Series X: Slide Listing
  - Walking Mural performance by Asco on Whittier Bl. in East L.A. Patssi Valdez (left) as Virgen de Guadalupe-in-black, Willie Herron (center) as the mural that became bored with muralism as a static medium and decided to walk away from the wall. Gronk (right) as an Xmas tree in green chifon. The Walking Mural was performed on Dec 24, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Patssi Valdez in the Walking Mural. (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Untitled acrylic on cardboard work by Gronk on view at the Ahora Lo Veras exhibition at Mechicano Art Center, East L.A., Nov 1972 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Opening reception for Ahora Lo Veras exhibition with works by Herron/Gronk/Gamboa. Appearing in this image are (l-r) Natividad Cisneros, Cyclona, & Gronk. (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Semi-Familia, pen & ink on illustration board by Gamboa. This work appears on the back cover of REGENERACION and the original drawing was confiscated by customs officials in Mexico in 1973. Exhibited in Ahora lo Veras. (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Untitled acrylic interior mural on plaster and plywood at Mechicano Art Center. This work was painted for temporary duration and was whitewashed within 30 days by its creator (Herron). (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Instant Mural performance was created when Gronk taped Patssi Valdez and Humberto Sandoval to a liquor store wall in ELA. Many pedestrians and motorists offered assistance to remove the artists from the wall even though low-tack masking tape was the only adhesive which kept them in place. Instant Mural has been documented with several slides images from this series in New West magazine (1978) and MOCA 1985 catalogue. (Box 13, Folder 7-10)
  - Dia de los Muertos, 1974, at Evergreen Cemetery in Boyle Heights. Asco decided to 'crash' the quasi-religious event which was scheduled to include a mass and other pre-Columbian rituals. Asco arrived in a large envelope which had been delivered via airmail. Willie Herron appeared as a pilot-in-triplane, Gamboa as dark storm clouds and lighting bolt, Patssi Valdez was the universe, Gronk was staff photographer, and Humberto Sandoval defended the group in his Asco tank. (Box 13, Folder 11-16)
  - Suffercation was performed before a live audience and was filmed (appears in the silent Super-8 film. Asco). Gronk tapes Valdez until she can no longer see or breathe. She is eventually brought back to life. (1974) (Box 13, Folder 17-18)
  - First Supper (After A Major Riot), was performed by Asco (slide #19, l-r, Valdez, Sandoval, Herron, Gronk) on a traffic island which had been built over the site of a police mass shooting which had taken place in 1973 during a public protest demonstration which was linked to other demonstrations of that era. The site was located at Arizona street at Whittier Bl. (the mass shooting was documented by LA RAZA magazine and victims appeared on the cover of the L.A. Times in 1973. The surrounding buildings, sidewalks, and street were leveled and rebuilt, eliminating all physical evidence of the hundreds of shotgun shells which were utilized to secure order.) First Supper was Asco's all-clear signal to East L.A. in late 1974. (Box 13, Folder 19-20)
  - Asco signs their name in spray paint on all of the entrances to the L.A. County Museum of Art after being told by LACMA curator that Chicanos do not create art. Patssi stands on bridge entrance with names. This event is mentioned in the Asco essay in the CARA catlogue. 1972 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - An image used in the production of the Super-8 film "Cruel Profit" which was screened at the Chicanismo en el Arte exhibition at LACMA. The film was later destroyed with only a few clips saved and included in the silent super-8 film, Asco. Herron is engaged in acts of destruction with a doll in the original film. 1975 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Asco Waves Good-Bye. Street performance 1973 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Untitled portable mural by Herzon and Gronk, acrylic on masonite board. This mural was painted during the course of year and was exhibited in various sites. This image (l-r, Herron & Gronk) appeared in New West, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Gamboa in studio, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Dispursuit, mixed media on illustration board by Gamboa. Details of this work appeared in REGENERACION. 1972 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - ASCO (Herron, Gamboa, Valdez, Gronk) 1974 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Decov Gang War Victim, 1978This performance work was designed to break the cycle of gang retribution killings by providing 'victims' which would neutralize the need for additional murders. (Gronk on street) (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Star Party, 1976(slide #29. l-r, Dee Dee Diaz. Patssi, Valdez, Gronk, Billy "Star" Estrada.) (Box 13, Folder 29-30)
  - Slasher #9, 1978Performance for Asco film whereby potential mass-killer victim is saved by slashing his own eyebrows. (Box 13, Folder 31-33)
  - The Gore Family performance in which a poor humble family is robbed by a thief as they attempt to sell their camera at the local pawn shop. The family is transformed into sadistic and cannibalistic predators. The Gore Family was utilized as a pre-fotonovela slide show and was also filmed to be included and altered in Humberto Sandoval's Sr. Tereshkova (mentioned in the Asco essay in the CARA catalogue. Also, brief clips in the film Asco. (slide #39, on the floor, Sandoval, l-r. Herron, Valdez, Gronk.) 1976 (Box 13, Folder 34-38)
  - Asco, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 40)
  - Valdez, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 41)
  - Valdez, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 42)
  - Valdez, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 43)
  - Valdez, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 44)
  - Valdez, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 45)
  - Spray-paint mural by Valdez included in No Movie exhibition at LACE, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 46-47)
  - Waiting For Tickets at the Music Center, (a No Movie). Valdez and Billy Estrada, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 48)
  - Billy "Star" Estrada, 1981(Passed away in 1994 due to AIDS) (Box 13, Folder 49)
  - Vogue, (a No Movie). Billy Estrada and Valdez, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 50)
  - Search and No Seizure. Billy Estrada and Valdez, 1977This image appeared in New West, 1978. (Box 13, Folder 51)
  - Gronk& Valdez, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 52)
  - Gronk, Valdez, Gamboa, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 53)
  - Betty Salas and Friends at LACE party, 1978This image appeared in MOCA 1985 catalogue. (Box 13, Folder 54)
  - Fernando Torres as bride-to-be at LACE party, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 55)
  - Herron. 1976 (Box 13, Folder 56)
  - Sandoval.. 1979 (Box 13, Folder 57)
  - Detail from Gronk section of Centro Chicano mural at USC (a mural painted by Gronk & Herron in 1973.. The building was demolished in 1977) (Box 13, Folder 58)
  - Black & White mural by Herron (1) and Gronk (r). Estrada Courts Housing Projects, 1979. (painted 1974-1980 (Box 13, Folder 59)
  - Detail of Black & White mural. section painted by Herron portrays Gronk as "Popcorn" in the 1971 pre-Asco performance, Stations of the Cross (this performance documented in MOCA 1985 catalogue). (Box 13, Folder 60)
  - Death of Fashion, 1980, performance by Asco for documentary film, Mur Murs by Agnes Varda. Valdez in red cellophane as a candy out of the box. The skull mural painted by Herron. The high heal shoe by Gronk (Box 13, Folder 61)
  - Death of Fashion, burns the present in order to write a future from the ashes. (Gamboa) (Box 13, Folder 62)
  - The Titanic, (l-r: Betty Salas, Valdez, Herron, Daniel Villarreal-) performance of a farewell party that was sinking fast! 1980 (Box 13, Folder 63)
  - The Titanic (Therese Covarrubias) (Box 13, Folder 64)
  - The Titanic (l-r: Humberto Sandoval, Cyclona, Willie Herron, Betty Salas, Patssi Valdez, Gronk, Diane Gamboa, Linda Gamboa, Victor Martinez, Therese Covarrubias, Daniel Villarreal, Gamboa) (Box 13, Folder 65)
  - Don't Not, 1984fotonovela (accompanying audio tape included in Stanford collection) performed by Humberto Sandoval and Lorraine Ordaz. This fotonovela was presented before a live audience at Galleria de la Raza, SF (Box 13, Folder 66-74)
  - A black & white version of this image appeared on the cover the La Comunidad section of LA OPINION special edition on "La Cultura Chicana". 1980 (Box 13, Folder 75)
  - Sit & Wait, 1981, performance (l-r: Gronk, Sean Carrillo) (Box 13, Folder 76)
  - Lunch at Woolworth's, downtown Phoenix (l-r: Gronk, Gamboa) 1983 (Box 13, Folder 77)
  - Last Rites in the Left Lane. 1951performance. (l-r: Therese Covarrubias, Sean Carillo). (Box 13, Folder 78)
  - Last Rites in the Left Lane. the 4th Street bridge at Lorena street was blockaded during a silent vigil. (Box 13, Folder 79)
  - Last Rites in the Left Lane (l-r: Daniel Villarreal, John Valdez, Alfred Arteaga, Martha Covarrubias, Richard Duardo, Gronk. Therese Covarrubias, Sean Carrillo, Paul Arevalo [passed away in 1995 due to AIDS], Gamboa, Jerry Dreva, Willie Herron) (Box 13, Folder 80)
  - Chicano Cinema. 1976No Movie (Gamboa). This image was documented in A Traves de la frontera (Mexico) exhibition catalogue. (Box 13, Folder 81)
  - Resist, Resist, Revolt, 1978mixed media installation by Gamboa in No Movie exhibition at LACE (Box 13, Folder 82)
  - Exterior mural by Roberto Gil de Montes and Gronk near Valley Bl. shopping area in El Monte. This mural created a controversy for its pro-revolutionary image which was El Monte city officials. The mural was whitewashed after the city officials created an ordinance requiring prior approval of imagery which will adorn public/private exterior walls. 1978 (Box 13, Folder 83)
  - Asco Float, 1979Dia de Los Muertos parade float, pushed and pulled by Asco and members of the community across various streets thoughout ELA. Painted and constructed by Herron and Gronk. (Box 13, Folder 84)
  - Pseudotourguoiser. 1981videotaped performance and closed-circuit videocast on CSULA system. (Text published in DE COLORES journal. Image l-r: Gronk, Betty Salas, Gamboa) (Box 13, Folder 85)
  - Gronk, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 86-87)
  - Illegal Landscape, 1981exhibition of interior mural works Gronk and Herron in which they created works during length exhibition period to be completed on last scheduled day at which time reception for artists occurred. Public was invited to dialogue with artists during creation of works. These two slide images show Gronk works. (Box 13, Folder 88-89)
  - Sticker Shock, 1983performance by Gamboa presented before a live audience in display window facades located in abandoned building entrances. (Box 13, Folder 90)
  - X's PARTY, 1983fotonovela (accompanying audiotape included in Stanford collection) performed by Therese Covarrubias and Daniel Villarreal. This fotonovela was presented before a live audience at UC Santa Cruz, Hispanic Urban Center (L.A.). and alleyway screenings in ELA. X's PARTY appears on the cover of the book Chicanos and Film, edited by Chon Noriega. (Box 13, Folder 91-98)
  - JETTER'S JINX, 1985conceptual drama. performed by Gronk and Humberto Sandoval, written by Gamboa, at L.A. Theatre Center. (Manuscript included in Stanford collection). Reviewed by L.A. Times and High Performance magazine. (Box 13, Folder 99-100)
  - SHADOW SOLO, 1983performance of conceptual drama at U.C. Santa Cruz. Shadow (Daniel Villarreal) and Solo (Sean Carrillo). Text published in Chismearte. (Manuscript included in Stanford collection). (Box 13, Folder 101)
  - Diane Gamboa. 1985with paintings on view at Armory for the Arts. Albuquerque, NM (Box 13, Folder 102)
  - URBANOISE. 1985performance by Gamboa at Armory for the Arts, Albuquerque. (Box 13, Folder 103)
  - Polaroid SX-70 photographs presented in GAMBOA 81 exhibition at Galeria otra Vez, ELA 1981 (Box 13, Folder 104-108.)
  - BW version of this image appears with "Chicanos Inside/ Outside the Mainstream", LAICA JOURNAL. (Audiotape interviews with the artists for this essay included in Stanford collection. l-r: John Valadez, Barbara Carrasco, Daniel J. Martinez, Diane Gamboa, Gronk, Patssi Valdez). (Box 13, Folder 110)
  - DEEP END DANCE, 1982fotonovela (accompanying audiotape included in Stanford collection) performed by Robert Beltran and Teri Nogales. This fotonovela was presented before a live audience at U.C.L.A (Box 13, Folder 111-116)
  - From CLUB LIMBO, these images are from one-of several fotonovelas which were presented during a performance of stories by Gamboa and Max Benavidez. Each performer told his stories in written, multimedia. and improvised manner. Each performer was unaware of what the other stories would be and there was no rehearsal prior to performance before live audience at Concert Hall, U.C. Irvine. (Manuscripts and accompanying audiotape for Gamboa's stories included in Stanford collection. This fotonovela performed by [#117] Barbara Carrasco and [118-119] Apolina Vargas.) CLUB LIMBO featured in LA OPINION. All U.C. Irvine performances were commissioned by Dr. Eloy Rodriguez and the International Chicano Studies Program during 1986-1994. (Box 13, Folder 117-119)
  - ON HANDS AND KNEE, 1989performance by Gamboa in which the artist crawls the distance from downtown L.A., across the 6th Street bridge into East L.A. as part of the Urban Refuse series. Similar image documented in L.A. STYLE Mar 1990 (Box 13, Folder 120)
  - DOOMESTIC LIFE, 1986fotonovela (accompanying audiotape included in Stanford collection) performed by (l-r), Barbara Carrasco, Diego Gamboa, Daniel J. Martinez. Presented before a live audience at Al's Bar, L.A (Box 13, Folder 121)
  - From CLUB LIMBO. This fotonovela performed by (l-r) Diego Gamboa and Ricardo Gonzalves. (Box 13, Folder 122-123)
  - HOMELESS, SWEET HOMEBOY, 1939performance by Diego Gamboa in which he sought (and was refused) shelter from 100 random people in L.A. County as part of the Urban Refuse Series. (Box 13, Folder 124)
  - NO FENCE TO MEND, 1989performance by Anthony C. Sandoval in which he traveled on foot from a fixed point in downtown L.A. to another point by going in a straight line even if it required cutting through barriers such as chain link fences and trespassing across private property as part of the Urban Refuse Series. (Box 13, Folder 125)
  - ANTIZONA, 1987intermedia performance at U.C. Irvine which recreated the visual/audio environment of the downtown L.A. intersection of Broadway and 7th Streets in a theatre setting. The media-based urban ambiance served as the backdrop for performers George Silva (appears in #126) and Diego Gamboa who both portray the child and adult version of the same person who grew up in a cardboard box to become a street preacher. The image in this slide is from a series of images in which the street preacher prays in public and occasionally stops traffic as he crosses many streets blindly leaving his fate to good brakes. ANTIZONA also incorporated videos in which people give answers to questions which are not revealed to the audience (the videos, question, performance script, audiotapes are included in the Stanford collection). (Box 13, Folder 126)